Christopher Goodwin

User Experience Developer

(802) 540-5036

hello@christophergoodwin.me
christophergoodwin.me
linkedin.com/in/goodwinc

About

With accessibility and usability in mind, I specialize in translating designs into scalable and maintainable code. Prioritizing browser-native behavior, I use semantic HTML, modular CSS, and lightweight JS to build experiences that empower and delight users.

Experience

Senior User Experience Developer at Kajabi

6/2022 - 4/2023

- Spearheaded the development, implementation, and maintenance of a new StencilJS component library with an emphasis on improving interoperability, accessibility, and scalability
- · Constructed, refined, and tested legacy React component library with a focus on backward compatibility
- Established and documented accessibility, semantics, and performance best practices to ensure consistency throughout new projects
- · Triaged, managed, and resolved component library support requests

Senior User Experience Developer at DockYard

9/2016 - 6/2022

- · Lead UX development for web apps with renowned companies such as Apple, Netflix, and Sparta Science
- · Collaborated with Design and Engineering team members to translate designs into semantic, reliable code
- · Wrote and audited code to ensure accessibility, performance, and graceful degradation
- Defined and refined code standards, to enhance company understanding of UX best practices and maintain consistent code solutions between developers
- · Mentored colleagues seeking to improve their UX, accessibility, and remote work skills
- Implemented inclusive hiring practices to reduce bias
- Co-worked remotely with a distributed team while actively fostering culture and engagement

Front End Web Developer at CIEE

8/2014 - 9/2016

- · Built, iterated, and implemented templates to maintain uniformity between products and websites
- Estimated timelines and scoped work to meet project deadlines
- Maintained and updated over twenty marketing websites

Skills

- HTML and CSS expertise with a specific focus on semantic, accessible, responsive, mobile-first code
- Front-End JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and StencilJS experience
- SaaS product development
- Familiarity with test/coverage suites
- Robust understanding of accessibility best practices
- Expertise in building, maintaining, and scaling complex and intricate design systems and component libraries
- Modern design software experience
- Years of remote work experience

Education

BS, Web and Interactive Media

- Pennsylvania College of Technology
- The Art Institute of New England

Certificate of Completion

Center for Technology, Essex